Guide to the Andrew Forest Muir papers MS 017
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas
- Series V: Alphabetical subject research files, 1935-1969, 252462
  - Railroads, 252601
    - Columbus, San Antonio & Mexican Gulf Railroad, 252613 (Box 62, Folder 11)
    - Columbus, San Antonio & Rio Grande Railroad, 1850s-1860s, 252612 (Box 62, Folder 12)
    - Buffalo Bayou, Brazos & Colorado Railroad, 1840s-1880s (folders 1-3), 252611 (Box 62, Folder 13-15)
    - Buffalo Bayou, Brazos & Colorado Railroad, 1840s-1880s (folders 3-6), 252610 (Box 63, Folder 1-3)
    - Galveston, Houston & Henderson Railroad, 1850s-1860s, 252609 (Box 63, Folder 4)
    - Galveston & Houston Junction Railroad, 1860s, 252608 (Box 63, Folder 5)
    - Houston Tap & Brazoria Railroad, 1850s-1870s, 252607 (Box 64, Folder 1)
    - Houston and Texas Central Railroad, 1850s-1870s, 252606 (Box 64, Folder 2-3)
    - Red River and Aransas Railroad, 252605 (Box 64, Folder 4)
    - Texas & New Orleans Railroad, 1850s-1870s, 252604 (Box 64, Folder 5)
    - Washington County Railroad, 1850s-1870s, 252603 (Box 64, Folder 6-7)
    - Various railroad related published materials such as charters and other documents, copied from the Texas General Land Office, 252602 (Box 65, Folder -)
  - Ranney, Roderick H., 252600 (Box 66, Folder 1)
    Episcopalian priest, missionary at Seguin 1855-1866, at New Braunfels 1867-1868, at Trinity Church in Galveston 1869-1872.
  - Reily, James, -1863, 252599 (Box 66, Folder 2)
    Colonel in Confederate Army, involved in development of Houston and in Federal and Confederate diplomacy (wife was a niece of Henry Clay).
  - La Reunion, 252598 (Box 66, Folder 3)
    French "communistic" colony (1854-1855) settled in Dallas County on Trinity River by Victor Prosper Considerant (La Societe de Colonisation Europeo-americaine au Texas or La Reunion); notes on the colony, correspondence on the colony, writings of V.P. Considerant; correspondence on research.
  - Rice, Elizabeth Baldwin (d. 1896) -- Orren Holt– will litigation (Rice vs. Holt), 252597 (Box 66, Folder 4)
  - Rice, William M. – Rice Institute Charter 1891, 252596 (Box 66, Folder 5)
  - Rice, William M. – Rice Institute land documents, 252595 (Box 66, Folder 6)
  - Rice, William M. – Rice Institute founding, first trustees, 252594 (Box 66, Folder 7)
  - Rice, William M. – Albert T. Patrick, 1866-1940, 252593 (Box 66, Folder 8)
  - Rice, William M. – Patrick's will of W.M. Rice (forged), 252592 (Box 66, Folder 9)
  - Rice, William M. – "A Man Morbidly Virtuous – Albert T. Patrick", an essay by AFM, 252591 (Box 66, Folder 10)
  - Rice, William M. – "Murder on Madison Avenue", an essay by AFM, 252590 (Box 66, Folder 11)
  - Rice, William M. – settling of estate with heirs, 252589 (Box 67, Folder 1)
  - Rice, William M. – valet, Charles Freeman Jones, 252588 (Box 67, Folder 2)
  - Rice, William M. – murder trial, 252587 (Box 67, Folder 3-4)
  - Rice, William M. – wills, 1964 Rice Institute charter trial, 252586 (Box 67, Folder 5)
  - Rice University vs. Waggoner Carr, Atty. General, State of Texas, 1963-64, re charter trial, 252585 (Box 67, Folder 6)
  - Rice University vs. John B. Coffee, appeal of charter trial decisions, 1966, 252584 (Box 67, Folder 7)
  - 'William Marsh Rice – Houstonian" by AFM, 252583 (Box 67, Folder 8)
  - 'William Marsh Rice, His Life and Death, The History of a Fortune" by AFM, 252582 (Box 68, Folder 1)
  - "William Marsh Rice and His Institute" by AFM, 252581 (Box 68, Folder 2-4)
  - Rice family members research & notes, 252580 (Box 68, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence regarding AFM's Rice research, 1950s, 252579 (Box 69, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence and notes regarding AFM's Rice research, 1950s, 252578 (Box 69, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence and notes regarding AFM's Rice research, 1950s, including transcripts of Rice's 1890s-1900 correspondence, 252577 (Box 69, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence and notes regarding AFM's Rice research, legal, financial (incl. Merchant Oil and Cotton Co.), family, 252576 (Box 69, Folder 4-6)
  - Richardson, Alfred Stephen, 252575 (Box 70, Folder 1)
  - Richardson, Walter Raleigh (Deputy County Clerk, 1850s, Grimes County), 252574 (Box 70, Folder 2)
    Episcopalian priest, former deputy county clerk in Grimes County, priest in Harris County, 1866-1869.
  - Ricord, John, 1812-1861, 252573 (Box 70, Folder 3-4)
    Lawyer of New York State, Texan immigrant 1835, private secretary to David G. Burnet, chief clerk of Department of State under Austin, a district attorney under the Republic of Texas, settler in Florida Territory, settler in Oregon, Attorney general of the Kingdom of Hawaii (1840s), attorney in California 1847, traveller in Central and South America, the Pacific, Asia, Africa, and Europe; notes on Ricord and Stryker families, era of the Republic of Texas. See also Microfilm, box 81.
  - Ricord, John, correspondence regarding Ricord, 252572 (Box 70, Folder 5)
  - Ricord, John, typescript copies of correspondence of Ricord, 252571 (Box 70, Folder 6)
  - Rising, Franklin Samuel, 252570 (Box 70, Folder 7-8)
  - River navigation notes, 252569 (Box 70, Folder 9)
  - Robinson, James W., 252568 (Box 71, Folder 1)
  - Rogers, Benjamin A., 252567 (Box 71, Folder 2)
    Episcopalian priest, to Texas 1850s, rector of St. Stephen's Mission Episcopal Church (Houston) and the Episcopal Church at Hempstead (late 19th century).
  - Rolls / military, Texas, 1850s-1860s, 252566 (Box 71, Folder 3)
  - Rottenstein, George, 252565 (Box 71, Folder 4)
    Episcopalian priest, missionary at Corsicana, Waco, and San Antonio (1855), former minister of Methodist Episcopal Church South (ca. 1849-1852), founder and first rector of St. Matthew's at Dallas, 1857. Died 1868.
  - Rucker, Lindsay Powell, 1815-1890, 252564 (Box 71, Folder 5)
    Anglican priest who organized Anglican parishes in Texas.
  - Rum, Romanism and Rebellion, 252563 (Box 71, Folder 6)
    Notes on Dowling and family, Civil War military techniques.
  - Ruthven, Archibald St. Clair, 1818-1865, 252562 (Box 71, Folder 7)
    British cotton merchant, resident of Galveston in 1840s and 1850s, father of James Ruthven (also a visitor to Galveston).
  - Saladee, Cyrus W., 252561 (Box 71, Folder 8)
  - Salmon, Richard, 1797-1849, 252560 (Box 71, Folder 9)
    Anglican priest, missionary to Texas, Houston educator, 1837-1840.
  - Sansom, Henry, 252559 (Box 71, Folder 10-11)
    Episcopalian priest, at Christ Church (San Augustine) and Christ Church (Nacogdoches) 1848-1851, at Trinity Church (Marshall) and at Jefferson (1851), rector at Christ Church (Houston) in 1852, rector at Vicksburg, Mississippi, 1860s-1890s.
  - Santa Anna, 252558 (Box 71, Folder 12)
  - Science, 252557 (Box 71, Folder 13)
    Notes on references to scientific topics (mainly astronomy, geology, and meteorology) in newspapers of Texas, 1849-1865.
  - Scott, William Richard, 1824-1894, 252556 (Box 71, Folder 14)
  - Seelye, Sara Emma E.E. (alias Franklin Thompson), 1841-1898, 252555 (Box 71, Folder 15)
    Canadian-born woman who disguised herself as a man and joined the Union army during the Civil War.
  - Seely, Richard S., 1812/13-1871, 252554 (Box 71, Folder 16)
  - Shaver, Daniel, 252553 (Box 71, Folder 17)
    Episcopalian priest, at Bellville, TX, early 1860s; at Jefferson City, 1865.
  - Sheldon, H.L., 252552 (Box 72, Folder 1-2)
  - Shepherd, William Miller, 252551 (Box 72, Folder 3)
  - Silk culture, 252550 (Box 72, Folder 4)
    Brief notes on infant silk culture of 1830s in the Old South and Texas; notes from newspapers.
  - Silver, J. M. [Weir], 252549 (Box 72, Folder 5)
  - Slater, G., Rev., Galveston, TX, 252548 (Box 72, Folder 6)
    Anglican priest from University of Oxford (?), proposed school at Galveston (1841), at Houston (1841); correspondence on research.
  - Slavery, 252547 (Box 72, Folder 7)
    Notes on slavery in Texas (1839-1870) taken from newspapers, correspondence, papers of the Texas navy, city ordinances, coroner's records, criminal district court records, probate records, deed records, monographs, published letters, laws of the Territory of Orleans, marriage registers, baptismal registers, county commissioners court minutes, contemporary published sources, laws of texas Congress and legislature, Texas reports, church records, journals of the Texas legislature; bibliography.
  - Slaves, 252546 (Box 72, Folder 8)
  - Smith, Ambrose, Rev., 252545 (Box 72, Folder 9)
    Anglican priest from Ireland (1849), to Austin and San Antonio (1859), at Christ Church (Covington, Louisiana) in 1850.
  - Smith, J.B.T., 252544 (Box 72, Folder 10)
    Episcopalian priest, missionary at Anderson, TX in 1855.
  - Snell, Martin K., 252543 (Box 72, Folder 11)
    Merchant and soldier, Texas, 1850s
  - Sparks, Milton Howard, 252542 (Box 72, Folder 12)
  - Spring Creek County, Texas, 252541 (Box 72, Folder 13)
    Typescript of AFM article "Spring Creek County, Texas" for the Handbook of Texas, notes on residents of and on the county itself, taken from deed records, newspapers, acts of Congress of Texas, congressional journals, election registers, state records, probate records, district court records; correspondence on research.
  - Staley, Thomas Nettleship, Bishop of Honolulu, 252540 (Box 72, Folder 14-15)
  - Stanley, John H. Smythe, Harris County, 1850s, 252539 (Box 72, Folder 16)
  - Steamship Mariposa, schedules and ephemera, 1940s, 252538 (Box 72, Folder 17)
  - Steele, William, 1781-1857, 252537 (Box 72, Folder 18)
    Episcopalian priest, former Methodist minister, became Episcopalian priest in 1817, from Virginia to Tennessee, to Texas in 1839 (Harrison County, TX), at Border Episcopal Mission (on Texas-Louisiana Line) in 1840s, in Harrison County and Louisiana 1840-1857; correspondence on research.
  - Stevenson, Vernon King (photograph, n.d.), 252536 (Box 72, Folder 19)
  - Stewart, Mary: land deeds to Shermans, Erath County, 1882 and 1898, 252535 (Box 72, Folder 20)
  - Supreme Court, Texas, 1836-1845. Rules and cases., 252534 (Box 72, Folder 21)
  - Supreme Court, United States, 1847-1875, 252533 (Box 72, Folder 22)
    Texas cases before the U.S. Supreme Court; Texas attorneys admitted to practice before the U.S. Supreme Court.
  - Swan, William Alexander, Diocese of Honolulu, 1880s, 252532 (Box 72, Folder 23)
  - Telegraph in Texas, 1838-1867, 252531 (Box 73, Folder 1)
  - Terry, Benjamin F., 1821-1861, 252530 (Box 73, Folder 2)
    Notes on his life and family. Colonel of Terry's Texas rangers, planter of Brazoria County, and members of the Rangers: Andrew Jackson, Thomas Lubbock, William J. Kyle, Alexander Sessums, Thomas Washington Masterson, William Masterson (?), John A. Wharton.
  - Terry, David Smith, 252529 (Box 73, Folder 3)
  - Texas Company, 252528 (Box 73, Folder 4)
  - Texas Institute of Letters (membership information), 252527 (Box 73, Folder 5)
  - Texas in 1837 (research, correspondence and galleys for this volume edited by AFM), 252526 (Box 73, Folder 6-7)
  - Texas Republic, 252525 (Box 73, Folder 8-9)
  - Texas Republic and later, 252524 (Box 74, Folder 1)
  - Texas research notes, 1944, 252523 (Box 74, Folder 2)
  - Texas research notes, 1944-46, 252522 (Box 74, Folder 3)
  - Texas research notes, 1944-49, 252521 (Box 74, Folder 4)
  - Texas research notes, 1958, 252520 (Box 74, Folder 5)
  - Texas research notes, n.d. - 1950s?, 252519 (Box 74, Folder 6)
  - Texas research notes, 1960, 252518 (Box 75, Folder 1)
  - Texas research notes, 1967, 252517 (Box 75, Folder 2)
  - Texas research notes, 1968, 252516 (Box 75, Folder 3)
  - Texas research notes, Texas Telegraph and Texas Register, 252515 (Box 75, Folder 4)
  - Texas revolution, news of in Hawaiian press, 252514 (Box 75, Folder 5)
    Typescript copies of articles in the "Sandwich Island Gazette and Journal of Commerce" which refer to the movement for Texan independence, July 30-1836-April 22, 1837, and Feb. 23 1839.
  - Texas [State] Historical Association, 252513 (Box 75, Folder 6)
  - Texas Trading Association, 252512 (Box 75, Folder 7)
    Business papers of this Harrisburg firm (founded 1827) operated by the Clopper family.
  - Texas assorted photostatic maps, plans, 252511 (Box 75, Folder 8)
  - Theron, Benjamin, 1805/6-1864, 252510 (Box 76, Folder 1)
    French and Spanish Consul, Inspector and Weigher at Galveston in 1850s and 1860s, expelled from Confederacy by President Jefferson Davis on suspicion of intrigue (1862).
  - Thomas, Effie, 252509 (Box 76, Folder 2)
  - Thompson, Algernon P., 252508 (Box 76, Folder 3)
  - Thompson, Henry, d.1840, 252507 (Box 76, Folder 4)
    Judge at Houston, poet, member of Christ Church, Houston.
  - Thompson-Nash Company building, Houston, 252506 (Box 76, Folder 5)
  - Thompson-Nash Company building, Houston, contracts, 252505 (Box 76, Folder 6)
  - Thurwachter, Heinrich, 1795/6-1859, 252504 (Box 76, Folder 7)
    German immigrant to Austin's Second Colony, soldier at San Jacinto, resident of Houston. (includes typescripts of AFM's essay "Heinrich Thurwachter, Soldier at San Jacinto")
  - Tomkins, Cecil Henry, Rev. 1930s, 252503 (Box 76, Folder 8)
  - Tompkins, Augustus M. (includes typescripts of AFM's essay "Augustus M. Tompkins, Frontier Prosecutor"), 252502 (Box 76, Folder 9)
  - Trader, Thomas Richard Bailey (Diocese of Louisiana), 252501 (Box 76, Folder 10)
    Episcopalian priest, rector of St. John's (Thibodaux, Louisiana) in early 1860s, rector of Christ Church, Houston, ca. 1869-1873.
  - Transportation (Texas, 19th century, including Galveston and Brazos Navigation Company correspondence), 252500 (Box 76, Folder 11)
  - Turner, Charles William (Diocese of California, 1870s), 252499 (Box 76, Folder 12)
  - Turton, Zouch Horace, 252498 (Box 76, Folder 13)
  - Union Land Company in Anahuac, 1831-1833, 252497 (Box 76, Folder 14)
    Immigration and mercantile company (1831-1833) which attempted to settle colonists on lands secured through Galveston Bay and Texas land Company; notes on the Union Land Company, James Prentiss, Henry Bowdoin Prentiss, Gen. E.A. Mexia, George Lewis Hammeken; list of colonial marriage bonds of Austin County (1824-1835); AFM article "The Union Company in Anahuac, 1831-1833, edited with an introduction by Andrew Forest Muir" (published).
  - Usborne, John (founder and rector of St. Clement's parish, Honolulu, died 1926), 252496 (Box 76, Folder 15)
  - Van Deerlin, Erasmus Jurian Hopman, b. 1846, 252495 (Box 76, Folder 16)
  - Wagiver, Edwin A., Christ Church Cathedral, Houston, 1860s, 252494 (Box 77, Folder 1)
  - Wainwright, Richard, Rev., Hawaii, 1880s, 252493 (Box 77, Folder 2)
  - Wallace, George, Rev., Hawaii, 1880s, 252492 (Box 77, Folder 3)
  - Ward, Jeremiah, 1845-1935, 252491 (Box 77, Folder 4)
    Episcopalian priest, member of First Virginia Irregular Cavalry (Moseby's Guerillas) 1861, captured 1863, released 1865, to Texas with Bishop Gregg of Texas, served at St. Stephen's Church, Huntsville from 1873, Rector at Christ Church (Laredo, Rector Emeritus at Christ Church (Laredo), ca. 1910-1935.
  - Warren, Edward, Rev., Hawaii, 1860s, 252490 (Box 77, Folder 5)
  - Washington County, TX, 1850s-1860s, 252489 (Box 77, Folder 6)
  - Watts, S.C. - research by, 252488 (Box 77, Folder 7)
    Notes concerning Eduardo Garay, subsecretary of Exterior Relations for Mexico (late 19th century), references on Mexico in the late 19th century, Elizabeth Bell Da Gama, Jorge Hammeken y Mexia, Masterson family, Enrique A. Mejia, James Frank Dobie, Sen. Rienzi Johnston, bibliographies on Britain, Carrie A. nation, August Santleben, Gouvernior family of New England, John Southerland, M.D. of Bexar County.
  - Wavell, Arthur Goodall, 1785-1860 (British military), 252487 (Box 77, Folder 8)
  - Webb, Walter Prescott, 252486 (Box 77, Folder 9)
  - Webber, John Ferdinand, 1793-1882 (Army of the Republic of Texas), 252485 (Box 77, Folder 10)
    Member of Austin's Colony, miscegenist, farmer, Unionist who fled to Mexico, pensioner of the United States; notes on his life and activities; typescript of AFM article for the Handbook of Texas supplement; correspondence on research.
  - Weymouth, Albert Blodgett, 1839-1913, 252484 (Box 77, Folder 11)
  - Whalley, Herbert Francis Edward, Diocese of Honolulu, 1880s, 252483 (Box 77, Folder 12)
  - Wharton family - Austin family, Brazoria County, TX, 1774-1879, 252482 (Box 77, Folder 13)
    Notes on these families and others of Brazoria County; notes on C.R. Wharton papers in Fondren Library.
  - Whipple, George Brayton, Diocese of Honolulu, 1860s, 252481 (Box 77, Folder 14)
  - White, Evelyn Hayward, typescripts of manuscripts, 1806-1864, 252480 (Box 77, Folder 15)
  - White, James Taylor, Texas property and land, 1850, 252479 (Box 77, Folder 16)
  - White, Joseph M., 1781-1839, 252478 (Box 77, Folder 17)
    Congressman from Territory of Florida, expert on British, Spanish, French, Mexican and Texan civil law on land titles, partisan of Texas Republic, delegate, Texas House of Representatives, 1825-1837.
  - Whiting, Henry, 1793/4-1853, 252477 (Box 77, Folder 18)
    Physician and resident of Harris County, living in vicinity of battle of San Jacinto, accused of being a "tory" during the Texas Revolution.
  - Wigfall, Louis Trezevant, 252476 (Box 77, Folder 19)
  - Wilbur, Sidney, 252475 (Box 77, Folder 20)
  - Williams, Thomas Jay, 252474 (Box 77, Folder 21)
  - Williamson, Charles George, 252473 (Box 77, Folder 22)
  - Willis, Alfred A., Rev., Anglican Episcopal Bishop of Honolulu, 1870s, 252472 (Box 77, Folder 23-24)
  - Willis, Alfred, Bishop of Honolulu (printed materials only), 252471 (Box 78, Folder 1)
  - Wills of various Texans (typescript copies), 252470 (Box 78, Folder 2)
    Transcripts of wills and related papers (1823-1863) of: James Bowie (1833), H.L. Arick (1852), John Birdsall (1839), William Boyd (1838), Patrick Braidy (1839), Andrew Briscoe (1848), Andrew M. Clopper (1852), Merrit M. Coats (1823), John DeBrot (1830), Charles L. Dell (1853), Daniel Dolan (1838), George Elder 91853), Edward E. Este (1842), Spencer Glasscock, James Grant (1835), Robert Griffith (1837), Thomas Hand (1837), Alexander Hodge (1836), George Ireland (1838), Gabirel Long (1837), Nathaniel Lynch (1837), Marshall Mann 91838), Jacob Maybee (1838), Laban Medifee (ante 1845), John W. Moore (1845), S.B. Raymond 91855), William H. Rogers (1836), James Routh (1837), Elizabeth Rundell (1852), Hal G. Runnels (1857), John Schnell (1859), William Smallwood (1844), James H. Stevenson (1856), Melinda G. Stockbridge (1858), John Taylor (1846), John Thornton (1863), George Williams (1842), John W. Moore (1845), Chauncey Goodrich, M.D. (1836), Felix Huston (1856); incomplete index of wills in Harris County (volumes A-Z, 1-11, for years 1836-1858)
  - Woo, Yee Boo, Rev., Honolulu, 1890s, 252469 (Box 78, Folder 3)
  - Wright, Stephen Richardson, 1812-1857, 252468 (Box 78, Folder 4)
    Episcopalian priest, Rector, Christ Church, Matagorda, 1855-1857
  - Wynns, Archibald, 1850s, 252467 (Box 78, Folder 5)
  - Yates, Andrew Janeway, 1810s-1820s, 252466 (Box 78, Folder 6)
  - Young, John Freeman, 1820-1885, 252465 (Box 78, Folder 7)
    Episcopalian priest, Missionary to Brazoria County 1848, St. John's Church, Brazoria County, 1849; Bishop 1867.
  - Young, Matilda Jane (Fuller), 1826-1882, 252464 (Box 78, Folder 8)
    Botanist, authoress, correspondent, expert on Texas flora, superintendant of Houston public schools, selections from her works.
  - Duplicate copies of articles and essays by AFM (originally represented in corresponding research files), 252463 (Box 78, Folder 9)
- Series VI: Original treasury notes and manuscripts, 1763-1908, 252377
  This material was collected by Andrew Forest Muir and dates mainly from the Republic of Texas Era and the U.S. Civil War era, reflecting everyday life through local (county, city, state, Confederate) currency, correspondence, receipts, military orders, and more.
  - Subseries A: Treasury notes, 1832-1872, 252449
    - Album #1: 43 items of Texas Civil War currency from 25 cents to $5. Also includes one railroad ticket from Shreveport, LA to Vicksburg, Miss., 12 Feb 1872., 252461 (Box 79, Folder 1)
    - Album #2: 43 items of Texas Civil War era currency from 25 cents to $5., 252460 (Box 79, Folder 2)
    - Album #3: 29 items of Texas and Confederate currency, 1838 to 1862, 25 cents to $100, and T & R R T, $40., 252459 (Box 79, Folder 3)
    - Album #3: 33 items of Texas and Confederate currency, 1838 to 1862, 25 cents to $100. Also one certificate each for Galveston and Brazos Navigation Co. ($100) and T & R R T ($40)., 252458 (Box 79, Folder 3)
    - Album #4: 55 items of Civil War currency, southern states, but not Confederate or Texas currency, 10 cents to $20., 252457 (Box 79, Folder 4)
    - Album #5: 31 items of Texas Treasury Warrants, Civil War period, $3 to $100. Includes C.S.A. $1500 bond, Houston, 22 June 1864., 252456 (Box 79, Folder 5)
    - Album #6: 55 items of Texas Treasury Warrants, Civil War period, $1 to $20. Includes C.S.A. exchange certificate $1200 "old issue", 17 November 1864., 252455 (Box 79, Folder 6)
    - Album #7: 58 items of Texas Treasury Warrants, Civil War period, $1 to $100. Includes C.S.A. exchange certificate $80 "old issue", 31 March 1865., 252454 (Box 79, Folder 7)
    - Album #8: 37 items, "shinplasters", Texas and Louisiana, Civil War period, 25 cents to $10., 252453 (Box 79, Folder 8)
    - Album #9: 30 items, "shinplasters", Texas, mainly Houston, Civil War period, 12.5 cents to $5. Also includes CSA blank exchange certificate; Amnesty oath, J.D. Andrews, Houston, TX, 13 July 1865; Republic of Texas naturalization certificate for J.D. Andrews, 1 May 1837., 252452 (Box 79, Folder 9)
    - Album #10: 10 items, State of Texas proclamations and executive orders, 1848 to 1861., 252451 (Box 80, Folder 1)
    - Treasury notes, various, Texas, City of Houston, Georgia, Confederate States, 252450 (Box 80, Folder 2)
  - Subseries B: Manuscripts, 1763-1908, 252418
    - Military, 252435
      - Military vouchers to feed Delaware Indians, 1795, 252448 (Box 80, Folder 3)
      - Order: Lt. Col. Franks, will have the short / 6 pdr in readiness to fire on the Church / (without delay) in order to support an / attack on Etournes House this night / at 8 o'clock -- / 10 Dec'r 1835 / Quarters in Bexar -- / by order of Col. Johnson / Com'd in Chief / Robert Morris / Major / N.B. / The order for /firing will be duly / communicated --/, 252447 (Box 80, Folder 4)
      - Certification of John Coleman sworn in as soldier, City of Austin, 1840, 252446 (Box 80, Folder 5)
      - Mss circular of 1st New Jersey brigade, Nov. 5, 1861, 252445 (Box 80, Folder 6)
      - Military telegraphs, 1862 (United States Army), 252444 (Box 80, Folder 7)
      - Receipt for Confederate quarter payment, 18[6]3, 252443 (Box 80, Folder 8)
      - Headquarters, 5th Brigade, Indiana Infantry Volunteers, Hebron, Mississippi, Pass, 19 Jan. 1864, 252442 (Box 80, Folder 9)
      - Military hospital requisition 1865 and cavalry pass 1864, 252441 (Box 80, Folder 10)
      - Order: No. 639 / Galveston Texas June 30th 1865 / William James of B Company Cooks / Regiment / Hvy Arty C.S.A. residing in / Galveston Texas having been, with the approval of / the proper authorities paroled, is permitted to return to his home, not to be dis- / turbed by the United States authorities, so long as he observes his parole and / the laws in force where he may reside. / By order / Major general USA Gordon Garnger / HB / illegible / Capt & Pro Mar /, 252440 (Box 80, Folder 11)
      - Military career notes on Marcellus M. Crocker, d. August 26, 1865, 252439 (Box 80, Folder 12)
      - Military General orders No. 5, Headquarters 5th Military District, (State of Texas), 11 Jan. 1870, 252438 (Box 80, Folder 13)
      - Military General orders No. 6, Headquarters 5th Military District, (State of Texas), 13 Jan. 1870, 252437 (Box 80, Folder 14)